welcome to meditating with John gravity
I'm a cognitive psychologist the
cognitive scientists at the University
of Toronto where academically teach and
scientifically study phenomena like
mindfulness and related phenomena such
as Insight flow mystical experience
transformative experience higher states
of consciousness the cultivation of
wisdom and the aspiration to
enlightenment
I've been practicing the pasta
meditation and meta contemplation Tai
Chi Chuan and cheek on for over 29 years
and teaching and professionally for
close to 20 years if you join for the
first time welcome you should know that
this is a course and the introductory
course is not complete I suggest what
you do is go to the description the
notes in for this video in the narrow
spine links to the previous lessons do
the first lesson and you can keep
participating with us every day but
every preps Saturday or Sunday do
another one of the lessons so start
immediately with less than once you get
basics so you can participate and then
work your way on a weekly basis through
the lessons and you'll catch up with us
every other Monday we have a Darla's day
in which I teach a new principle new set
of practices that build on and layer
upon the previous practices that I've
taught yesterday was such a darling day
I will review that she come that I
caught yesterday Wednesday tomorrow and
Friday I'll review it in depth and go
through it with you again one note I put
a mark put the note in for me because I
recognize I wouldn't realize as soon as
I have spoken it as soon as we added
that like I gave you the wrong names for
things so there's a bit of confusion and
how people use the church econ so what I
think could have suggested this we used
cheek own for this whole set of
practices Jeong Jeong is the standing
postures and each on are the slow-moving
posture
they're both part of Chico although
people will often refer to just the
movie parts as Qigong but let's try and
use it that way I apologize for speaking
and it confused and confusing manner
yesterday what I hope this clarifies
things and then we'll we will I will
consistently use those terms and not
wait going forward I also haven't
announced tuck this over with
more and with Jason so alternative
Monday's like our Dharma days on the on
the off Mondays the Monday's that aren't
Dharma days those are going to be upaya
days papaya is spelt you pea aya and it
basically means skillful means and what
we're gonna do in a pioneer is I want
you guys to get a sense of the whole
thing because there's you're getting the
parts but I want you to see the Gestalt
I want to you see how the parts fit into
the whole and how the whole impregnates
the parts so on a pie today I will go
through the entire sequence with you
we will start with the cheek on
practices that we will move into sitting
and then we will finish with Lexi Oh
Davina so we will have a pie a day and
then on one Monday the next Monday will
be Dharma day the next Monday will be a
pie a day and then Dharma day and we
will continue doing that going forward
so that will give you because I as a
good teacher papaya also means pedagogy
as as a good teacher I know it's
important to both zoom in for the parts
and zoom out for the whole and give
people both of those levels of teaching
because that way they will internalize
it and develop it much more deeply so I
hope that's clear please like this
stream to increase the visit visibility
in the YouTube algorithm that will help
me to reach other people as I said for
previous lessons and see the description
and if you're joining for the first time
one more time do the first lesson then
start joining us every day doing a new
lesson every Saturday or something then
you'll catch up with us and you'll be
able to get incentive every day we said
Monday through Friday should say every
weekday we said from
3210 sometimes a little bit later than
ten especially on dharma day and i guess
no on you piyo day but there's a Q&A at
the end please limit the Q&A to
questions concerning this course this
ecology of practices that I'm teaching
for more general comprehensive questions
please come to the live stream QA 3:00
p.m. Eastern Time every third Friday of
the month it'll be June 19th of this
month so I think that's everything
I can't think of anything else right now
other than to once again thank you all I
was on the discord server last night
some of you were there or night mark was
there Kareem I was there that was there
I really appreciate that and so I just
wanted to express my gratitude all right
so let's get in your posture
please let's set phones to do not
disturb and we will begin when I say
together begin
[Music]
slowly begin to come out if you practice
trying as best you can to integrate with
your cultivated in your practice your
everyday consciousness and cognition
perhaps by reciting the five promises to
yourself
all right we have time for a couple of
questions at music I don't know quite
how to pronounce it in Praja
is it appropriate to think of the
expanding meta outward as seeking
contact with the imminence of the one
and the past are seeking contact with
transcendence are born hmm it's
interesting I could see it going both
ways so meta is definitely opening us up
but I understand what you're trying to
get about the imminence of the one
you're trying to get that Center sense
of intimacy and Pastner is for breaking
frame opening you up I could see it
going that way but also see it the other
way I could see people and this would
put I just would like this that I'd say
it could be both ways that what I'm
expanding out caneta I and participating
in the morning
speaks of the transcendence of the one
and when I'm dissolving in the past not
that's moving towards the suchness of
everything the imminence of the one I
can see it going both ways and that goes
towards the fact that I like I said
before people's intuitions about Praja
like I said for many for most people but
not for everyone the expansion of the in
breath is meta the contraction right is
a pasta but for some people the reverse
makes more sense so I can see both
working and it probably interacts with
the fact that different people have
different sort of intuitive senses of
how to map proje
on to the breathing yeah sorry I'm not
trying to be cavalier I don't see any
principles reason for saying no but I
also think you could make an equally
good case for meta giving you contact
with transcendence and the pasta giving
you contact with imminence the inner
miss of things and Mehta is the
outwardness of things the transcendence
so I don't have that's particularly
helpful answer but that's I think I
think it's the it's the best answer I
can give the most honest answer I can
give which I think matters so this is a
Tuesday so we don't have as much time
I'm happy for the question
remember tomorrow I will be doing I will
go through it all again an extensive
review of all the cheek on both the
standing Jen John and the moving each
one also remember the Friday that we're
coming I sorry the money that we're
coming up to the next calendar Monday
will be our first entire day in which I
will do the entire sequence of practices
with you the cheek on the sitting and
Alexia you know I want to thank you all
for joining
there's always nurturing and nourishing
to me to be here I'm going to thank my
dear friend and techno major bar for
everything he's doing behind the scenes
and I was always Jason was here with me
helping many of you know yesterday he's
handling the camera and moving things
around my beloved son is always here
helping please subscribe to the channel
to be notified of the next video on my
channel you'll find the lecture series
awakening from the meeting Chris's and
the dialogo series the discussion series
voices with rebecky
explore all of these ideas and the wider
full by the assaut fiha way of life that
encompasses them invite others who might
benefit by sharing this series many of
you are doing that and I appreciate that
I thought we'd help as many people as
possible
Brett is here pleasure of doubt there's
a link to the discord server there's a
group of people there who are doing this
practice and then they'd Alexio
afterwards and they're exploring how to
integrate Luxio with the logos and with
the mindfulness practice i had the great
pleasure at being there last night
6 o'clock Eastern Time forth every other
week
seeing Monday's is like you burn a date
I have going discord server I guess it's
a it's a multiple d-day go on discord
server and how the QA Anika I just had
an amazing time last night it's
questions are so thoughtful and
thought-provoking and reflected both of
a commitment of thought and a commitment
in practice that I want to honor so
please if you can go to the discord
server right after this and meet that
community maybe people who are
practicing it's it's a great benefit we
are doing this every weekday morning
9:30 Eastern Time please remember
continuity of practice is more important
than quantity there is no enemy worse
than your own mind and body
there is no friend no ally no true
companion of the path better than your
own mind and body elapsed unto yourself
I'll see you all tomorrow
take good care everyone